crossfitinvictus.com 2019-02-16

# Invictus Fitness Terms of Use

## INVICTUS FITNESS PRIVACY POLICY, TERMS OF USE & GDPR COMPLIANCE

Invictus Fitness (Invictus) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Invictus has updated our privacy policy to provide you with increased transparency into the personal data it collects, how it is used, and the controls you have over your personal data. By using the crossfitinvictus.com website, and all affiliated Invictus Fitness pages, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

For information on specific aspects of our GDPR compliance, please click the appropriate link below.

  1. Privacy Policy and Use of Website
  2. Terms and Conditions
  3. Terms of Service
  4. Data Protection
  5. Data Processing and Automatic Logging
  6. Cookie Policy
  7. Request record of your data

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact the Invictus Fitness Data Protection Officer at [GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com](mailto:GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com).

## 1\. Privacy Policy and Use of Website

This Privacy Policy sets forth the policies and practices with respect to information or data that is received or gathered regarding members, visitors and users (collectively “you” and “your”). [www.crossfitinvictus.com](https://www.crossfitinvictus.com/) and all related sites of Invictus Fitness may be referred to collectively as “www.invictusfitness.com”, “Invictus Fitness”, “CrossFit Invictus”, “us”, “we”, “Site”, “Website” or “the Company”.

CAREFULLY READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY BECAUSE BY YOUR USE OF THIS SITE AND ITS SERVICES YOU WILL BE EXPRESSLY SIGNIFYING THAT YOU AGREE TO THIS POLICY AND THAT YOU ASSENT TO THE TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT, INCLUDING THE USE OF ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT YOU SUPPLY OR THAT IS COLLECTED ABOUT YOU AS DETAILED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT EXPRESSLY AGREE WITH ALL OF THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS SITE OR ITS SERVICES.

## 2\. Terms and Conditions

### Copyright and Trademark Rights

The texts, images, graphics and the layout of this website displayed on this website are subject to copyright. Violations of this will be prosecuted both under civil and criminal law. Reproduction of all or part of this website is only permitted with the prior written consent of Invictus Fitness. The individual use does not authorize the transfer of content to third parties. Trademarks used on this website are protected and all rights are owned by the respective trademark owners.

### Disclaimer

Invictus Fitness can not be held liable for any loss or damage of any kind resulting from the use of this website or the inability to access it, be it due to system maintenance or any technical malfunction, or otherwise. 

Invictus Fitness assumes no guarantee or liability for the completeness, accuracy and timeliness of the information provided on its website. It is your responsibility to independently review the content that is made available to you through this website and our services.

Our websites contain links to other websites, like our partner’s websites or links to booksellers, that may offer information, products or services that our customers might find useful. These sites may request information from you. In such instances, the collection and use of your personal information will be governed by the privacy policy applicable to that site. We do not control the privacy policies, contents or links that appear on these sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third-party sites or services before providing any of them with your personal information.

### Communication

The sending and receiving of emails serves to speed up the communication and the preparation of general communication, business deals or the support of customer service. On the way from sender to recipient, e-mails could be read, falsified, lost or misdirected and delivered late. For these reasons, contracts and declarations of intent by e-mail can not be concluded effectively or deemed as handed over to our company. These statements and any legal notices will become effective only after written confirmation by you. 

Any liability of our company for claims that could be based on communication by e-mail is excluded.

By accepting communication by email with our company you accept these conditions. It is your responsibility to ensure that information and content that you download to your systems or otherwise select is checked for viruses or other destructive features.

## 3\. Terms of Service Regarding Financial Information

### General Information

The information on the websites of Invictus Fitness and publications published in our name are exclusively for private use. Invictus Fitness makes no representation that the information on these websites or in our publications is suitable or usable for other services and ancillary services.

### Data Protection

For us, Invictus Fitness, the protection of your personal data is a very important concern. It is therefore natural for us to deal with your personal data in compliance with the applicable legal data protection provisions.

With this privacy policy we explain to you which data in the context of the use of this website are collected, processed and used for which purposes and which rights you are entitled to.

### Data Collection and Processing When Visiting Our Website

As is usual with many websites, the retrieval of the individual web pages from our web servers and the web analytics software Google Analytics we use automatically collects and processes the following non-personal data:

### Collection and Processing of Personal Data and Consent

We collect, process and use personal data such as your name, postal address, email address or other contact details **only if they have been entered by you on the website and transmitted to us** and to the extent that such collection, processing and use is permitted by law or covered by your consent.

Our site uses an order form for you to purchase information, products, and services. We collect your contact information (i.e., mail and e-mail addresses), financial information (i.e., credit card numbers), and demographic information (i.e., zip code and state). We use this contact information from the order form to send you a confirmation email for which you cannot opt out. We also use this information to send you your orders, as well as information about our company and products and special promotions. Your contact information is also used to get in touch with you when necessary for additional information to process or fulfill your order. Financial information that is collected is used to bill for products and services only. Financial information is not retained or stored as part of your shopping profile, so you must enter your credit card number each time you place an order. Unique identifiers are collected from Web site visitors to verify your identity and for use as account numbers in our record system. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to help us improve our website and our product and service offerings.

### Surveys and Sweepstakes/Contests

From time to time, we may conduct online surveys to help us better understand and serve your needs, or conduct sweepstakes or contests. These offers may ask for contact information (i.e., email address), financial information (i.e., credit card numbers), and demographic information (i.e., zip code, age, or income level). We may use this contact data from our surveys to send you information about our company. Unique identifiers are collected from the Web site to verify your identity. We use this data to help us improve our Web site and our product and service offerings.

### Information from Other Sources

For reasons such as improving personalization of our service (i.e., providing better product recommendations or special offers that we think will interest you), we might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. We also sometimes receive updated delivery and address information from our shippers or other sources so that we can correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily.

In addition, if your prior consent is required for certain data collection, processing and use, such as service telephone calls and the use of our newsletter or our information e-mails, we will, of course, ask you for your consent beforehand at the corresponding section of our website ask. These declarations of consent are recorded by us and can be accessed by you at any time at the appropriate place on our website. We recommend that you print out the declarations of consent for your own documents. **You are entitled to revoke your given consent at any time in whole or in part with effect for the future.** Even such a revocation will be logged by us.

In compliance with GDPR, your data will be destroyed upon request. 

## 4\. Data Processing

Personal data processed during a financial transaction, or inquiry may include:

  * Identification data, e.g., names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses, business contact information;
  * Personal characteristics, e.g., date of birth, country of birth;
  * Identifiers issued by public bodies, (if you are doing business with us as a vendor) e.g., tax identification number;
  * Cookie information, e.g., cookies and similar technologies on websites and in emails (please see also our Cookie Policy).

## 5\. Automatic logging

Our web servers automatically save every access or retrieval of a website or file belonging to our website temporarily in a log file. The following data is stored until its automated deletion after evaluation by the web analytics software Google Analytics we use:

  * IP address of the requesting computer
  * Name and URL of the called file
  * Date and time of access
  * Transferred amount of data
  * Message if the retrieval was successful
  * Identification data of the browser used and the operating system of the requesting computer
  * URL of the referring web page, if access was via link, and additionally search term, if access was via search engine
  * Name of your Internet access provider

Any data that can not be assigned to specific person(s) is not personal data. This data, or a transfer of this data does not automatically result in the creation of a personal user profiles. The processing of the data takes place exclusively for the purpose of enabling the use of the website (connection establishment), for internal system-related purposes such as technical administration and system security purposes and for the needs-based design and optimization of this website using our web analytics software Google Analytics.

## 6\. Cookie Policy

Our web servers store so-called “cookies” in the memory of your browser, ie small text files with data that serve the technical session control, in particular the identification of the browser for the duration of the visit to the website. These cookies will be deleted automatically 120 days after your visit to our website. They facilitate the navigation through our website and allow us to optimize the website to your needs and anonymous evaluation of the general user behavior based on the number of visitors.

When you visit any of our websites, a cookie may be placed on your computer for a number of reasons, such as (a) to keep track of your shopping cart, (b) to recognize you when you return to our site, (c) to recognize whether a customer came to our site as a result of a promotion or advertisement with one of our partners sites or email campaign and (d) to track the sales made by customers referred to us from a 3rd party so that they can receive compensation under our affiliate program. If you choose to not have your browser accept cookies from crossfitinvictus.com websites, you may not be able to view all the text on the screens, or to experience a personalized visit, or to subscribe to certain service and product offerings on our sites.

We also collect anonymous visitor information about how you utilize our site, such as IP addresses, browser types (such as Internet Explorer, Safari, Mozilla, etc.), referring pages and pages visited. We use this information (a) to perform anonymous statistical analysis of Web page traffic patterns, (b) to administer our Website and servers, and (c) to improve our services.

Of course you can also view our website without cookies. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. [You can prevent the storage of cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/) or be warned of cookies by saving your browser by setting your browser settings accordingly. You can find more information about these functions in the help menu of your browser. However, you may be exposed to some of our website features, web pages, or parts thereof, e.g. For example, if you restrict the use of cookies, you can use them only to a limited extent or not at all.

### Clear GIFS (“Web Beacons”)

Clear GIFs, also known as “web beacons” or “single-pixel GIF’s” are very small images (typically 1 x 1 pixel) that help websites understand their customers better. While any type of file can operate as a web beacon, clear GIFs are most popular because their very small file size prevents them from interfering in the websites’ operation. Clear GIFs function like cookies, in that they are used to track and measure online actions taken by website users. In contrast to cookies clear GIFs are not stored on a user’s hard drive, but are embedded into the graphics, text or other components of web pages. Web pages and graphical emails use codes that tell your computer what to do when a page is opened. While they typically contain text and graphics that you see on the screen, often web pages also contain instructions or tags’ that then ask the website’s server to send you further content (such as an image or a block of text that changes frequently). Web beacons are retrieved in the same way as the text and graphics that you see on a website or in an email, and the action of calling the material from another server allows the event to be counted. When a user’s browser requests information from our Site we may use GIFs to gather “passive” information such as the IP address of your computer; the time the material was viewed; the type of browser that retrieved the image; and the prior existence of cookies from our Site. This is information that could be gathered through the use of cookies. Web beacons do not give any “extra” information away. They are simply a convenient way for us to gather the simple statistics and manage cookies. Clear GIFs may be used by third parties to monitor activity on the Site. Turning off the browser’s cookies will prevent web beacons from tracking your specific activity, but web beacons may still record an anonymous visit from your IP address.

### Facebook

Facebook Tools are used on the website and may use cookies, web beacons, and other storage technologies to collect or receive information from your websites and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target adds. You can opt out of the collection and find more information on your choices here: http://www.aboutads.info/choices and http://www.youronlinechoices.com/.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is activated on this website, your IP address will be shortened by Google beforehand within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data.

You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. In addition, you may prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading the browser plug-in available under the following link and install (http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### Google Remarketing and Google Conversion Tracking

Like many other websites, this website uses Google Remarketing, a web service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google uses so-called cookies, small text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. The IP address is then shortened by Google for the last three digits, a clear assignment of the IP address is therefore no longer possible. Google complies with the US Safe Harbor Privacy Policy and is registered with the US Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program. Google will use this stored information then use your other sites to selectively display interest-based ads from us, Google, or third parties based on previous visits to this site. To this end, Google may also link this information with other anonymous usage data and transfer it to third parties, if required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Google will never associate your IP address with other Google data. You may disable the use of cookies by Google by using the [Google advertising opt-out page.](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous?sig=ACi0TChS6ioGWYjsRwxSkDVTtbrJuegXe3bxbQEUjYR0QatVz41li57ma7sQFuv5FjEt72sF_UnnjBH_fiVD9koBk5HPDJqCUpbSVc5php-f76cL8N7aYoQ&hl=de) Alternatively, you can disable the use of third-party cookies by visiting the [opt-out page of the Network Advertising Initiative. ](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) We point out, however, that in this case you may not be able to use all functions of this website in full.

Like many other websites, this website also uses the Google AdWords online advertising program and, as part of that, Google Conversion Tracking to measure which websites our ads work best on. Google AdWords sets a cookie on your computer if you’ve reached this website through a Google ad. These cookies lose their validity after 540 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit certain pages of this website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and we may recognize that you clicked on the ad and were redirected to this page. Each advertiser receives different cookies. Cookies can not be tracked through the websites of advertisers. The information obtained by using the conversion cookie is used to determine which visitors have triggered a specific action on our site through advertisements. We learn the total number of users who clicked on our ads, and which clicks resulted in an action. However, we do not receive any information that personally identifies a user. If you do not wish to participate in the tracking process, you can clear or disable the Google Conversion Tracking cookie from your Internet browser under User Preferences by setting your browser to block cookies from the domain “googleadservices.com”. You will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the context of Google Remarketing and Google Conversion Tracking in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Please refer to [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy.html) before using this website if necessary.

### Data Transfer

The personal data collected as part of the use of this website will not be disclosed to third parties or transmitted in any other way. Exceptions to this are transfers of personal data to our data processors, government institutions and authorities, as well as private rightholders on the basis of legal regulations or judicial or regulatory decisions and the transfer to state institutions and authorities in the event of attacks on our legal interests for legal or criminal prosecution purposes. External service providers that we use to operate the website or to perform certain services on our website, process personal data exclusively on our behalf and are contractually obliged to comply with the applicable statutory provisions on data protection and data security. They are not considered third parties in terms of data protection law.

### How We Protect Your Information

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and to ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. We shall continue to take reasonable steps to provide effective data protection at all times, however, no security technology can provide invulnerability to information compromise. Therefore Invictus Fitness cannot, and does not, guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to us or to any third party affiliated with the Site. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer.

## 7\. Your rights

### Information and Information Rights

At any time you have the right to information about the data stored about you, their origin and recipient as well as the purpose of the storage. You may request the data we have stored by sending us an email to [GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com](mailto:GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com) or you can send us a written request to: Invictus Fitness 1401 E Street San Diego, CA 92101. If you have any questions about our privacy policy or if you wish to receive more detailed information, you can also contact us at these addresses.

### Security

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.

We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer.

### Choice/Opt Out

We only collect and hold your email address in order to send information and services you have specifically requested and to notify you of new developments, products, services, trainings, events and occasional recommendations for organizations that we feel offer products or services that our customers might find useful. You can unsubscribe at any time. If we send you an email, it will contain an opt-out link which you can click to have your name removed from our email list.

If you supply us with your contact information online (postal address, telephone and cell phone numbers, etc.) online, you may receive periodic mailings, calls, text messages, etc. from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such contact, please let us know by sending us an email to [GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com](mailto:GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com). Please provide us with your exact name, address and telephone numbers so we can remove you from our contact database.

### Correct/Update

Our customers can correct, access and update pertinent Personally Identifiable Information obtained through the site. Mechanisms include online, email, telephone, postal mail etc. This helps to assure that the information we collect is accurate and up to date. You can correct, access, and update your personal information by emailing [GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com](mailto:GDPR@crossfitinvictus.com), or you can send us a written request to: Invictus Fitness 1401 E. Street San Diego CA 92101.

### Conditions of Use, Notices and Revisions

If you choose to visit Invictus Fitness, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of the law of the state of California. Our business changes constantly. This Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the Privacy Notice in effect at the time of use.

### Parental Consent

Our Sites are not directed to children under the age of 13 and we will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. We strongly recommend that parents participate in their children’s exploration of the internet and any online services and use their browser’s parental controls to limit the areas of the internet to which their children have access.

### Change of Privacy Policy

From time to time, it may be necessary to change this privacy policy, for example as a result of the further development of our website or legal changes. Invictus Fitness therefore reserves the right to change the privacy policy at any time with effect for the future. We therefore recommend that you read this privacy policy again at regular intervals.

**_Updated May 24, 2018_**
